houkago futari de sugoshita kyoushitsu
Whenever we're together in the classroom after school
tsukue no ue muchuu de hazumu kimi no koe
You at your desk, just talking and talking on and on
donkan na kimi no sono taido ga
You're so dense, and it really shows
itsumo watashi wo ijiwaru ni saseru no
And that's why I always have to pick on you
hitoribocchi da to omou toki mo aru
Sometimes I feel like I'm alone
namida tomerarenai hi mo aru
Some days I can't stop myself from crying
hontou no watashi wo mitsumete hoshii no
I want you to look and see the real me
kitto tsutawaru to shinjiteiru yo
I'll keep believing that one day you will
kimi wa itsudatte itsudatte kawaranai kara
But you just never, ever, never, ever change, and so
watashi ga nankai mo nankai mo signal okutteageru
I keep sending and sending and sending and sending the same signal
yume mita ano oka mezashite
Dreaming of the day I'll make it over that hill
kujikesou na toki mo ganbaresou da yo
Even when I feel like giving up, I can keep going on
kimi ga iru kara
Because you're there for me
Friend, Foe, or a New Character?
（倫也）…で
俺を呼び出した理由は？
So, why did you call me here?
（英梨々）あたし　困ってるの。
Well, you see, old chap,
I'm caught in quite the predicament.
そう。
トテモ　トテモ　困ッテマ～ス。
えせイギリス人のまねは　やめろ！
Drop the fake British accent!
英語の成績　俺より悪いくせに。
Your English grades are even worse than mine.
夏コミの原稿が
そろそろ　ヤバいのよ。
We're running low on time to get
our Summer Comiket manuscript done.
まっ　そんなことだろうと
思ったけど。
I had a feeling it was about that.
For the record, I have certainly not been slacking off!
言っとくけど
サボってたわけじゃないわよ！
Thanks to you pushing unreasonable
amounts of work on to me, I had a late start.
だいたい　あんたが
色々　無茶な作業を　ねじ込むから。
いつもより　スタートが遅れて…。
I know that.
分かってる。
責任は取るつもりだ。
I intend to take responsibility for it.
えっ　せっ　せせ…
責任　取るの？
T-Take responsibility?
So, what do you want me to do?
…で　俺は　何をすればいい？
えっ！？
設定の確認？
Go over the setup?
Put a Summer Comiket notice on the homepage?
ホームページの夏コミ告知？
印刷所の交渉？
Negotiate with printing places?
Rather than looking at the storyboard,
ネームより　ストーリーとか
シチュエーションを→
I want you to help me come up
with the premise and plot.
一緒に考えてほしいの。
Wait just a second.
いや　ちょっと待て。
同人誌作りは　素人だぞ　俺。
You do know how amateur
I am at this doujin thing, right?
そんなことは　百も承知よ。
Believe me, I do.
でも　今は　重度のアニ豚である
あんたに頼るしかないの。
But at this point, turning to an anime freak
like you is the only choice I have!
Even if relying on you is like relying on a single
easily broken arrow, or like grasping at straws.
そう。　それが
すぐ折れる　一本の矢であろうが→
あっという間に沈む
アシであろうが。
ものすごく　モチベーションの下がる
励ましを　ありがとう。
Thank you so much for
that incredible demotivation.
とにかく→
Look, once this is done, I'll work on the character design
for our game, so shut your mouth and help out.
これが終わったら　ゲームの
キャラデザに　入ってあげるから→
今は　黙って手伝いなさい。
How can I share ideas with my mouth shut?
黙ってたら
ネタ出し　できないだろ？
それで　ジャンルは？
What's this based on, anyway?
The Snow Prism.
『あの雪のプリズム』
The Snow Prism
Oh, I know that one!
あ～　あれか！
全話　見たぞ　俺。
I've seen all of it!
It was the number one anime this spring!
春クール
ナンバーワンだったよな。
Yeah, I know.
（英梨々）知ってる。　もともと
あんたのブログで　知ったんだし。
It was on your blog that I
heard about it in the first place.
そっか　そっか。
I see, I see.
うん。　それなら
手伝えるかもしれない。
Maybe I can help you out, after all.
There's no "maybe" here!
今の言葉　聞いたわよ。
You never had a choice!
もう　断るのは　なしよ。
So, what kind of story are you doing?
で　どんな話にする？
A heartwarming continuation about Kouhei and Ui,
the protagonist and main heroine would be nice.
俺は　やっぱり
メインヒロインの羽衣と→
主人公の公平との→
ほのぼのした
アフターストーリーなんかを…。
うん。　アフターストーリーよ。
Yeah, it'll be a continuation, all right!
幼なじみヒロイン　麻里子との
イチャ　ラブ　エッチのね。
But about making hot passionate love
to the childhood friend, Mariko!
Wait, hang on just a minute!
待て　ちょっと　待て。
As if I can I help it.
I'm on Team Mariko, after all.
仕方ないでしょ。
私　麻里子派なんだもん。
I mean, Ui's too flawless. She's like a doll.
だって　羽衣って
あまりに八方美人過ぎて→
人形みたい。
It's like she's only being
pulled along through the story.
まるで　物語に
無理やり　動かされてる感じ。
You know that's not what I have
a problem with! Don't play dumb!
いや　そこを気にしてるんじゃ
ないでしょ。　そうじゃないでしょ。
お前　男の俺を
巻き込んでおきながら→
You're getting me, a man, involved in
making 18+ content with you?!
１８禁　作るつもりか！？
If it hasn't got sex in it, it won't sell.
エロがなきゃ売れないのよ。
エロを売るなよ　未成年！
You're a minor! You can't sell it with sex in it!
売るのは　パパとママだから。
That's why my mom and dad are going to sell it!
作るのは　法的に問題ないから！
There's nothing illegal about me making it!
I'm not sure that's what
the derivative work guidelines say.
二次創作ガイドライン的には
微妙なんじゃないか？
This is not the time to discuss
the shady side of the doujin world!
今は　そんな同人の闇に
触れてる場合じゃないの！
さあ　あんたは
主人公の公平に成りきるのよ。
Now, you're going to act out
Kouhei, the protagonist,
and you're going to passionately whisper
loving words to me—wait, no—to Mariko!
そして　あたし…　じゃなかった→
麻里子に　情熱的に
愛を　ささやきかけなさい。
Come on, get started.
（英梨々）ほら　早く。
おっ　おう。
Uh-huh...
Hey, you should smile, Mariko.
なあ…　笑ってよ　麻里子。
こっ　公平。
K-Kouhei...
うん　それだよ。
Yeah, like that.
You look cutest when you're smiling.
お前は　笑顔が
一番　カワイイんだからさ。
So I hope from now on,
you'll always be smiling by my side.
だから　これからも
ずっと　俺のそばで笑ってて…。
Y-Yeah.
うれしい。
I'd like that.
By the way, why did you
have to change clothes for this?
てか　何で
わざわざ　着替えてんだよ。
Well, it's our first time and everything.
だって
これが　私たちの初めてなんだし。
That wasn't me acting. I'm talking to you, Eriri.
今のは　せりふじゃなくて
英梨々に聞いてんだけど。
今の　あたしは　麻里子なの。
Right now I'm Mariko!
Don't get caught up in idle thoughts.
余計な雑念に　惑わされるな。
いまいち　釈然としないぞ。
Don't think you can dodge the question like that.
Come on, keep going!
ほら　次よ　次。
分かったよ。
Fine.
で　ここから
どうすればいいんだよ。
So, what should we do from here?
Well...
そりゃあ…。
I guess we better get started.
そろそろ　始めるしかないでしょ。
そっ　それって。
Y-You mean...
Hurry up! We're running out of pages!
早く。
もう　ページ数も　ないんだから。
じゃあ　いくよ。　麻里子。
Here we go then, Mariko.
痛いっ。
ごめん　大丈夫か？
Ow!
Sorry, are you okay?
だから　そんな　ページ数ないって
言ってるでしょ。
Didn't I just tell you we
don't have many pages left?
あんたは　早く　動きなさい。
Just get a move on already!
O-Okay!
おっ　おう！？
もっと…　もっと愛して。
More... Show me more love.
Didn't I just tell you?
さっきから　言ってるだろ。
I love you more than anything in the world.
愛してる。　世界で一番。
言葉だけじゃ…　嘘っぽいよ。
You can't convince me... with words alone.
じゃあ　どうしたら
信じてくれるんだよ。
Then what can I do so that you'll believe me?
めちゃくちゃにして。
Mess me up.
二度と　忘れられないくらい→
Do something to me so amazing
that I'll never forget it.
すごい…　こと　して。
Don't get out of character now!
You'll make me want to die!
素に戻るな！
死にたくなるでしょ！
School resumes Thursday, August 5
Be careful not to get into any accidents over summer break
≪加藤。　今日という今日は
はっきり言わせてもらうぞ。
Katou!
Today, I'm finally going to tell you
something I've been meaning to say.
Have you even been holding
anything back before today?
≪（恵）安芸君が　言いたいことを
我慢した日なんて→
今まで　あったっけ？
いいから　聞け。
Never mind that. Just listen.
You have zero understanding
of what a character is really about.
お前は　キャラクターというものが全然　分かってない。
Yeah, I guess you're right.
（恵）ああ　うん。　そうだね。
Their personality, manner of speech, birthday, measurements, favorite underwater Mobile Armor...
性格　言葉遣い
誕生日　スリーサイズ。
好きな　水中専用モビルアーマー。
These are the important points
that define a character.
こういう　キャラクターを構成する重要な要素は→
そんな簡単に
変えちゃいけないんだ。
You can't just go changing them.
そんなことしたら　読者の愛した
加藤　恵というキャラクターは→
That would be the end of the Katou Megumi
that readers fell in love with!
死んでしまうんだ！
Really? I suppose that is an issue.
（恵）そっかあ。　それは大変だね。
なのに　どうしたんだよ！？
How could you do this, then?!
（恵）何が？
Do what?
何で　いきなり
髪形　変えてくるんだよ！
How could you completely overhaul your hairstyle all of a sudden?!
（恵）えーっと…　何となくかな。
Um... I just felt like it.
何となくだとぅ！？
You just felt like it?!
加藤！　お前は
そんな　単なる思い付きで→
Katou, you would dare whimsically take such a gamble
that could completely destroy your character?!
キャラ崩壊にも
つながりかねない→
危険な賭けに
打って出たというのか！？
Well, look, this happens in
manga sometimes, doesn't it?
（恵）あ～　でも　ほら
漫画とかでも　時々　あるじゃない。
（恵）髪形を変えたヒロインが
急に　注目を集めたりするのって。
Like, when heroines change their hairstyle one day and suddenly become noticed.
集めてないじゃん！
But you aren't being noticed!
Almost everyone but me is
looking straight through you!
俺以外　スルーされてんじゃん！
加藤！
うーん　終業式ってのも
微妙だったよね。
I guess pulling it off at a
closing ceremony is a bit tricky.
やるなら　始業式だったかな？
Maybe the opening ceremony
would've been better.
だいたい
そんな変化球に頼ってたら→
You'll never be a first-rate main heroine
relying on cheap tricks like this!
いつまでたっても
一流の　メインヒロインになんか→
なれないぞ！
Protesting about a girl's hairstyle so much
must mean you're paying some attention, right?
女の子の髪形を
そこまで否定されると→
少しは　思うところがあるよね…。
（石巻）それで　澤村さんは
夏休み　どこか行くの？
So are you going anywhere
during the break, Sawamura-san?
Huh? Oh, um...
えっ？　ええっと…。
出掛けるわけないじゃない。
この　くそ暑いのに。
As if I'm gonna go out in this freaking heat.
（里見）えっ？
（英梨々）そっ　そうね。→
G-Good question.
特に　決まってはいないけど→
I haven't decided on anything, but I might go to
our villa in Nasu or to my dad's family home.
那須の別荘か
パパの実家くらいかな。
（里見）お父さんの実家っていったら
イギリスだよね？　すごーい。
Your father's home is in England, right?
That's amazing!
（石巻）もしかしたら
お城に住んでたりして。
He doesn't live in a castle or anything, does he?
ううん。
別に　大した所じゃないわよ。
No, it's nothing special.
一度も行ったことないけど。
Not that I've ever been there.
Understand, Katou?
≪いいか　加藤！
It's not little tricks you can randomly come up with
that latch onto the hearts of the readers.
俺たちの心を
がっちり　つかまえるのは→
思い付きの小細工なんかじゃない。
長い時間　かけて
磨き抜かれ→
It's the classic traits that have been polished and proved through time!
研ぎ澄まされた定番なんだ。
Ah, you mean like blonde twintails
or long black hair?
ああ。　金髪ツインテールとか
黒髪ロングとか？
ＯＫ　そうかもしれない。
Okay, those are good examples.
そうかもしれないが
今は　髪形に　こだわらずに→
But let's set aside the matter of hairstyle
and talk about overall character.
キャラクター全体について
語ろうじゃないか。
じゃあ　ツンデレ系幼なじみとか
毒舌系先輩とか？
So, like the tsundere childhood friend
or the sharp-tongued senior?
Sure, yes, you have those too.
そうだな　そういうのもあるよな。
だが　定番といえば
それだけじゃあるまい。
But there are plenty of other
classic character types.
Such as?
（恵）例えば？
Well, let's see...
そうだな…。
例えば　妹系後輩なんか　どうだ？
How about... the little sister-like junior?
あっ　後輩なんだ。
本物の妹じゃなくて。
Oh, you just mean a junior,
not an actual little sister.
リアル妹は
色々な方向に　物議を醸すから→
Well, a real little sister would cause controversy,
so let's not go there right now.
今は　やめといた方がいいんだよ。
I see. One man's meat is another man's poison.
そうなんだ。
世間も色々あるんだね。
それは　ともかくっ！
But back to the point!
「先輩」って呼んできて
ぴったり　くっついてきて→
Imagine a younger girl always calling out "Senpai,"
sticking to you like glue, looking up at you in admiration.
上目遣いに見上げてきたりする
後輩の女の子とか→
超　萌えるだろ？
Isn't that so incredibly moe?
（恵）えっと…
私　まだ　「萌える」って言葉が→
Um, I'm still not used to conversations where "moe" is used as a real word.
一般動詞だっていう前提で
話すのに　慣れてないんだけど。
How great it would be to see her leaning against
the school gate, waiting to leave together with you!
そんな女の子が
校門の柱に　背中を預けて→
出待ちなんか　してくれたら
最高だろ？
（出海）倫也先輩！
Tomoya-senpai?
そう！　そんなふうに！
Yes, that's exactly what I mean!
（恵）えっ？
（英梨々）うん？
（出海）やっぱり！
やっぱり　倫也先輩だ！
I knew it! It is you, Tomoya-senpai!
よかったー。　やっと見つけた！
I'm so glad! I've finally found you!
（出海）帰ってきたよ。
私　先輩の所に　帰ってきたんだよ。
I came back.
I came back to you, Senpai!
Senpai!
（出海）先輩！　先輩　会いたかった。いや…。
Okay...
Senpai, I missed you!
This is taking the classic a bit too far.
定番にも　程があるだろ。
本当に　出海ちゃんなんだな。
Is that really you, Izumi-chan?
やだ。　当たり前じゃないですか。
Oh, you...
Of course it is!
もしかして
忘れちゃったんですか？
Don't tell me you forgot about me.
あっ　いっ　いや…。
No.
Hashima Izumi?
（詩羽）波島　出海？
Yeah, I'm pretty sure that's what her name was.
確か　そんな名前だった。
So she's your and Mr. Ethical's junior?
（詩羽）あなたと倫理君の後輩？
（英梨々）
んっ。　あたしは知らない。→
I don't know a thing about her.
小学校　違うし　２学年も下だし。→
We went to different elementary schools, she's two years below,
and above all, she moved to
Nagoya before middle school.
何より　あの子　中学に上がる前に
名古屋に引っ越してしまったから。
それを知らないっていうのは
語弊があると思うのだけれど。
It seems a bit of a stretch to say you
don't know a thing about her, then.
とにかく　あたしは
あの子と話したことないの。
The point is, I've never spoken to her.
I only know her as some girl who was
always following Tomoya around.
いつも　倫也の後ろについて
歩いてたことしか　知らない。
So anyway, if she's two years below us
（詩羽）それにしても
２学年　下ってことは→
彼女　まだ　中学生よね？
that would mean she's still in middle school.
中学生レベルなのは
あなたの方だと思うのだけれど。
Funny, out of everyone here, you're the one
who seems most like a middle schooler.
Die in a fire.
（英梨々）滅びろ。
Do I really look that different?
そんなに
変わったように見えます？
You're practically another person.
いや　もう　別人。
You used to have really short hair,
and you were tan all the time.
ほら　出海ちゃん
昔はショートカットで→
真っ黒に　日焼けしててさ。
So you think I look a bit more girly now?
少しは　女の子っぽくなりました？
Yeah.
（出海）でも　もし　そうだとしたら
それは　先輩のせいなんですよ。
Well, if that's so, it's all because of you, Senpai!
先輩が　私に　女の子の喜びを
教えてくれたから…→
After all, you taught me
the pleasures of being a girl.
なんですよ。
Hang on a second.
ちょっと待って。　３年ぶりって
彼女　そのころ　まだ小学生だよね。
If you haven't seen each other in three years,
that means she was in elementary school then, right?
No, wait a minute, Katou!
えっ　いや　ちょっと待て　加藤。
俺が　出海ちゃんに教えたのは…。
All I taught Izumi-chan was—
（出海）だから　倫也先輩！
So, Tomoya-senpai...
（出海）これ　受け取ってください！
Please accept this!
We're Fancy Wave! We're on during
day two in the east hall, 29B.
（出海）「２日目　東　ヘ　２９ｂ」→
「Ｆａｎｃｙ　Ｗａｖｅ」です。
フフッ。　絶対に来てくださいね。
Come and see us!
I see.
そっか～。
出海ちゃん　同人　始めたんだ。
So you started doing doujin work, Izumi-chan.
And based on Little Love Rhapsody at that.
しかも
『リトルラブ・ラプソディ』本かあ。
Yeah! Last year was my first time in an event, so I'm a beginner.
はい。　とはいっても→
去年が　イベント初参加の
駆け出しですけどね。
ねえ　安芸君。
その　リトル何ちゃらってのも→
Hey, Aki-kun.
Is this Little Whatever a dating sim too?
ギャルゲーなの？
It's not "Little Whatever"!
（出海）
何ちゃらじゃありません！
It's called Little Love Rhapsody!
『リトルラブ・ラプソディ』です！
『リトルラブ・ラプソディ』
Little Love Rhapsody!
Also known as LitRhap or LLR!
他にも　『リトラプ』とか
『ＬＬＲ』とか呼ばれてて→
It's a popular trilogy with more than
two million copies sold, so get it right!
シリーズ３作で
累計２００万部をも超える→
人気シリーズなんですから
間違えないでください！
うん　分かった。
Okay, got it.
出海ちゃんが　間違いなく
安芸君の愛弟子だってことが。
You're a true disciple of Aki-kun, Izumi-chan.
I never played any games or watched any anime before I met Senpai.
私　先輩と会うまでは→
ゲームとかアニメとか
全然　見てなかったんです。
He took the ignorant young girl I was and showed me a whole new world.
そんな　幼くて
世間知らずだった私に→
先輩は
新しい世界を見せてくれた。
誕生日のプレゼントに→
He got me LitRhap 2 along with the
game console for it as a birthday present.
『リトラプ２』をゲーム機ごと
プレゼントしてくれたんです。→
先輩が　あのとき　『リトラプ２』を
プレゼントしてくれなかったら→
If Senpai hadn't given me LitRhap 2,
私は今　こんなに
ゲームやアニメ三昧の→
I wouldn't have the happy life of
games and anime that I have now.
幸せな人生を送っていなかった。
I'll never be able to repay him
for what he's done for me!
だから　先輩には　感謝しても
しきれないくらいなんです。
（恵）そっかあ。→
Oh, I see.
So this is the classic little sister-like junior heroine
you were talking about, Aki-kun.
これが　定番の妹系後輩ヒロイン
ってやつなんだね。　安芸君。
何かが違うような気が
しないでもない。
Somehow I have the feeling that's not quite it.
Not that I'm in any position to complain.
いや　俺が言うのも何だけど。
No, you really aren't.
本当に　何だかなあだよね。
So he corrupted a pure, innocent
elementary school girl with a dating sim.
純粋無垢な小学生の女の子に
乙女ゲームを与えるなんて→
昔から　女の子を腐らせる
手練手管は一級品ね　倫理君。
His ability to corrupt girls has
always been top notch, hasn't it?
LitRhap...
（英梨々）『リトラプ』…。
What's wrong, Sawamura-san?
どうしたの？　澤村さん。
N-Nothing. Nothing's wrong!
（英梨々）なっ　何でもない。
何でもないわよ。
Are you feeling unwell?
気分でも悪い？
If you need to visit the loser girls' corner,
it's at the slide. I'll walk you over.
滑り台なら　あっちよ。
連れていってあげるわ。
どうして　そこに
誘導しようとするわけ？
Why would I need to go there?
（出海）そんなわけで　先輩→
So, Senpai...
夏コミ　絶対　絶対　ぜーったい
来てくださいねー！
You definitely, absolutely, positively must come to Summer Comiket!
ああ。　絶対　行くから。
Sure, I'll definitely go.
出海ちゃんの新刊
楽しみにしてる。
I'm looking forward to seeing
what you've made, Izumi-chan.
See you, Tomoya-senpai, Katou-senpai.
それじゃ　倫也先輩
加藤先輩！
あっ　それから　澤村先輩も！
And you too, Sawamura-senpai!
えっ？　あっ　えっと…。
Huh? Oh, um...
出海ちゃん　澤村さんとも
知り合いだったんだ。
So you and Izumi-chan knew
each other as well, Sawamura-san.
No, I know her, but she doesn't know me.
（出海）いえ。
私が　一方的に　知ってるだけです。
After all, she was among the
biggest names in our school district.
だって　うちの学区じゃ
一番の有名人でしたもん！
Oh, one more thing, Senpai!
（出海）あっ　そうだ　先輩！
何？
What is it?
You should come over to
our new house sometime!
（出海）今度　新しい家にも
遊びに来てね。→
I'm sure my brother would
be happy to see you too!
きっと　お兄ちゃんも喜ぶし。→
じゃあ　さようなら～！
All right, bye!
あっ　ああ。　じゃあな。
Y-Yeah. See you.
ハァー。
Her brother would be happy to see me, huh?
「お兄ちゃんも喜ぶ」かあ…。
何か　怒ってるか？　さっきから。
Have you been mad about something?
Not really.
別に！
An old friend of mine just returned after three years.
３年ぶりに
友達が　こっちに帰ってきたんだ。
Isn't it natural we'd have a lot to talk about?
話が弾んで当然だろ？
I told you, I'm not mad.
You're just too self-conscious.
だから　怒ってないし！
あんた　自意識過剰！
勘違いも　甚だしい！
You don't understand anything!
Really? That's all right, then.
そっか　ならいいんだけど。
You're the worst, the way you just settle for whatever explanation suits you.
そうやって
自分に都合のいい解釈して→
勝手に安心する態度も最低！
どっちなんだよ。
Make up your mind already.
So you gave LitRhap to her.
『リトラプ』…　布教してたんだ
あの子に。
うっ…　そりゃ　名作だし。
Well, it's a masterpiece.
だって　あれは…。
But that's—
Long time no see, you two.
（伊織）久しぶりだね。　２人とも。
I want to see good works
enjoyed by as many as possible.
いい作品は　できる限り
たくさんの人に→
プレーしてもらいたい。
それが　オタクの本能だろう？
That's otaku instinct.
Otaku instinct is to not let someone inexperienced
jump right into a masterpiece!
いい作品だからこそ→
にわかに入ってきてほしくない
ってのも　オタクの本能よ。
Still, wouldn't you want a dear friend to
enjoy such a masterpiece as soon as possible?
それでも　相手が大切な
友達だったら　布教するだろ　普通。
（英梨々）今は　そんな一般論なんかどうでもいい！
I don't need your commonplace principles now!
（伊織）わざとだよね？
You're doing this on purpose, right?
You have noticed me here, haven't you?
（伊織）いくらなんでも
気付いてるよね？
じゃ　何だってんだよ。
So what's the problem?
I won't understand if you don't tell me!
はっきり言ってくんなきゃ
分かんねえよ。
You already know!
（英梨々）分かってるくせに。→
You know exactly what I want to say!
あんた　私の
言いたいこと　分かってるくせに。
（伊織）お願いだから
スルーしないでくれよ。
Can I ask that you not just ignore me?
（伊織）３０分以上前から　ここで
スタンバイしてたのに　台無しだよ。
I've been waiting here for more
than half an hour already.
What do you want, Iori?
何の用だよ　伊織。
Thanks to my father's work,
I've come back to Tokyo after three years.
父さんの仕事の都合で→
３年ぶりに　東京に戻ってきたからちょっと　挨拶にね。
I just came to say hello.
No need to come all this way.
わざわざ　帰ってこなくても→
You could have stayed in Nagoya
eating all the good food I've heard about.
うまいって評判の名古屋飯を
ずっと堪能してればよかったのに。
知ってるかい？　倫也君。
Have you heard, Tomoya-kun?
名古屋で有名な
ジャンボエビフライは→
There's a famous jumbo fried shrimp in Nagoya
that uses imported black tiger shrimp.
実は　輸入物の
ブラックタイガーを使っていて→
They call it a specialty when
it's not even a Nagoya food!
名古屋の名産でも
何でもないんだよ。
When Hakata's marinated pollock roe doesn't use
Kyushu-made cod roe, does anyone care?
そんなの　博多名物の
辛子めんたいこが→
九州産のタラコを　使っていない
時点で　どうでもいいだろ。
You two sure picked the most
insignificant thing possible to argue about.
（英梨々）ホント　どうでもいいこと争ってるわね　２人とも。
どうして　また　俺の前に現れた？
Why are you showing your face to me again?
I seem to recall severing ties with you.
お前とは　絶交したはずだ。
That's so cold, Tomoya-kun.
冷たいな　倫也君。
僕らは　昔　オタクの世界で→
Weren't the two of us once true friends,
agreeing to rise up through the otaku world together?
一緒に　のし上がろうと誓い合った親友同士だったじゃないか。
Sure, once upon a time we did say that.
確かに　そんな時期もあったよ。
クラスの中で　一番　イケメンで→
Finding out that you, one of the best looking guys
in class who I never thought I'd see eye to eye with,
絶対　話が合わないと思ってた
お前が→
まさか　俺を超える重度のオタだと知ったときの衝撃は→
were an even bigger otaku than I was came as
quite a surprise, and I still haven't forgotten it.
今でも忘れられない。
You think so?
（伊織）そうかな？
僕は　まったく　逆の印象だった。→
I had the opposite impression.
君だけが　僕のことを
分かってくれる→
I thought of you as the only person that would ever understand me.
ただ一人の人だって
思ってたんだよ。
い…　伊織。
I-Iori...
Do you know how many girls in your class were into that weird dynamic of yours?
（英梨々）あんたたちの
その紛らわしい　やりとりで→
クラスの何人の女子が釣れたか
知ってる？
けど…。
However...
けど　やっぱり　お前は
俺とは違う人種だった。
You were completely different from me, after all.
お前が　オタクになったのは→
You didn't become an otaku to enjoy and spread the things you loved.
好きな作品を楽しんだり
広めたりするためじゃない。
You just tried to get close to popular works
and creators to make yourself look important.
ただ人気のある作品や作家さんに
乗っかって→
自分を大物に
見せようとするためだった。
（伊織）最初から
言ってたじゃないか。→
I told you from the beginning.
My goal was to rise up through the world of otaku.
僕の目的は　オタクの世界で
のし上がることだって。
Then rise up yourself from the bottom!
なら　自分で
一から　積み上げてみろよ。
せめて　クリエーターの人たちを
食い物にするのは　やめろ。
Don't just feed on the creators!
Maybe you should try applying those exact words to yourself.
（英梨々）あんた　それ　そっくり
そのまま　自分に言ってみたら？
Iori!
伊織！
お前のやり方は間違ってる！
The way you're doing this is wrong!
そうかい？
お前だって　本当は→
Oh, really?
I'm sure even you realize that
what you do is underhanded.
自分のやっていることが
後ろ暗いんだろ？
That's why you couldn't even speak frankly about what you do to Izumi-chan, your own little sister?
だから　出海ちゃんには→
妹には　今の自分の姿を
見せないんだろ？
I wonder about that.
（伊織）さあ　どうだろうね。→
But one thing, Tomoya-kun.
けれどね　倫也君。→
Representative
This is who I am now.
これが　今の　僕さ。
Representative
あっ…。
「ｒｏｕｇｅ　ｅｎ　ｒｏｕｇｅ」って→
Rouge en rouge?
Kousaka Akane's circle?!
あの　紅坂　朱音のサークル？
Akane-san's very busy and rather fickle.
朱音さんが
多忙な上に　気まぐれな人でね。
今までも
色々　手伝ってたんだけど→
I've helped them out with many things,
so they couldn't turn me down anymore.
とうとう
断りきれなくなっちゃってさ。
ちょっと　待てよ。
Hold on.
Are we talking about the superstar creator
who's been in the spotlight for more than a decade?
それって
１０年以上　シャッター前から→
外れたことのない　超大手だぞ。
僕は　ここまで　のし上がった。
This is how high I've risen.
君が認めないやり方で
ここまで成功してみせたよ。
See how the methods you reviled
worked out for me?
I look forward to our fruitful relationship.
（伊織）どうぞ。
今後とも　よろしく。
あたしは　いらないわよ。
I don't need a business card
from a greedy doujin punk like you.
そんな　強欲な
同人ゴロの名刺なんて。
（伊織）いいや。
（英梨々）うん？
I can't have that.
You're the one I want to give one to most of all,
君には
ぜひ　受け取ってもらいたいね。
柏木エリ先生。
（英梨々・倫也）えっ？
Kashiwagi Eri-sensei.
（伊織）僕は…
いや　うちのサークルは→
I—no, my circle—is quite interested in you.
君に　とても興味がある。
You knew...
お前　知ってたのか？
英梨々の正体。
about Eriri's identity?
それだけじゃないよ。
That's not all.
We know all about what you're
planning to make, Tomoya-kun.
倫也君が　今　やろうとしてる
計画のこともね。
You're making a game with
Kashiwagi Eri and Kasumi Utako.
柏木エリと　霞　詩子で
ゲームを作る。
これが　どれだけ　オタク業界に
インパクトを与えるか→
You know what kind of impact this will have
on the otaku world, don't you?
本当は気付いているんだろ？→
君は　その企画の
プロデューサーなんだよ。→
You're the producer behind
this grand design, aren't you?
業界を震撼させる
仕掛け人なんだよ。
Aiming to send shock waves through the industry?
違う！　俺は別に
業界で　のし上がりたくて→
No! I'm not doing this to get
further up in the industry!
やってるわけじゃ…。
（伊織）けどね　倫也君。→
And yet, Tomoya-kun, my circle just so
happens to have exactly the same plan.
偶然なんだけど
僕のサークルでも→
ちょうど　同じような企画が
立ち上がっててね。
And we're searching for an artist for it.
（伊織）その原画家を
探してる最中なのさ。
何…　だと？
What... did you...
波島…　あんた…。
Hashima, don't tell me...
勝負だね。　倫也君。
伊織…。
It's a contest now, Tomoya-kun.
Iori...
Does your new, baby circle deserve to have Kashiwagi Eri on board?
（伊織）君の　できたばかりの
サークルが→
柏木エリを擁するに値するか。→
Or would she perhaps shine better with us?
あるいは　僕の
「ｒｏｕｇｅ　ｅｎ　ｒｏｕｇｅ」こそが→
彼女を輝かせるに
ふさわしいかのね。
bye-bye no ato samenai binetsu
After every good-bye, my cheeks are always warm
w
yokaze ni fukare kangaeru
And as I feel the wind against them, I always think
suki kirai kirai suki kurikaesu
Love? Hate? Hate? Love? Over and over
sono hitomi ni utsutteiru no wa
What are you seeing in those eyes of yours?
real sore tomo nijigen
Reality or something 2-D?
tayasuku kawaii da nante iwanai de yo ne
Don't just say I look pretty like it's no big deal to me
ashita mo me wo kosutte ohayou wo itte
Tomorrow, you'll rub your eyes and say "good morning"
tawai mo nai koto takusan oshiete
And talk about all sorts of pointless stuff
sukoshizutsu chikadzuiteku kyori ni
And as we slowly grow closer together
doushiyou jibun ja nai mitai da
What do I do? What am I usually like?
merry-go-round ga tomaranakute
This merry-go-round just never stops
mawaru mawaru keshiki ga kawatteku
Spinning, spinning, the scenery blurs by
colorful na yume wo miru
Like a colorful dream
dokudoku shite karadajuu wo
Throb, throb, I can feel them inside
meguru meguru kimochi
Going 'round and 'round, these feelings
mada kotoba ni dekinakute
I still can't put them into words
hitokoto sore de juubun nanoni
Even though one word would be enough